Cassidy Smith

Email: cassidysmith319@gmail.com

Phone: 347-860-0465

Self-taught front-end engineer and web designer. Recently redesigned and built the front ends for nobledesktop.com, training-nyc.com, and careercenters.com. Continue to support those sites and add new features. Proficient in semantic HTML, modern CSS/SASS, and JavaScript/ES6 with additional experience in Ruby on Rails. Currently learning React and Redux.

Experience

Front-End Developer & Designer—Noble Desktop, New York, NY

September 2017-Present

- Redesigned nobledesktop.com (100+ page Ruby on Rails website) in Sketch
- Led the front-end development of nobledesktop.com launched in July 2018
- Defined the CSS architecture and responsive layout strategy for the redesign
- Designed the UI for our new checkout process and built the front-end components

Graphic Designer—Noble Desktop, New York, NY

September 2015-September 2017

- Created new content and projects for Noble's in-house curriculum
- Created graphics and animated GIFs to promote new classes and seminars

Research & Development Assistant—iBall Instruments, Norman, OK

May 2014-June 2015

- Prototyped mechanical parts for iBall's gas chromatography equipment
- Designed electrical motor enclosure for hazardous location certification

Field Services Coordinator—Apogee Telecom, Austin, TX

August 2011-May 2014

- Submitted proposals for equipment upgrades based on network performance tests
- Managed support ticket queue and provided field support for students

Education

B.S. Mathematics—Oklahoma Baptist University

August 2011-May 2014 / 3.56GPA / SGA Senator

Language & Technologies

HTML5 / CSS3 / JavaScript / Ruby on Rails / SASS / Flexbox / CSS Grid / SVG / Git